Berat Ucar *Front-End Developer*



dev.beratucar@gmail.com
+905537457033

Ankara / Turkey in Berat UcarBerat Ucar ● Berat Ucar

Education

Frontend Developer, Bootcamp 10/2022 – 12/2023 New York, United States

Civil Engineering, Gazi University 09/2017 – 10/2022 | Ankara, Turkey

Skills

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, SASS, React.js, Redux.js, Postman API, REST APIs, Webpack, Unit Testing, NPM, SDLC, Jira, Scrum, Agile Methods, CRM, Git, Github, Autocad, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint

Languages

English (B2)

Turkish (Native)

Profile

Front-End Developer with 1+ year experience in the software development lifecycle (SDLC) in developing and designing user experiences of Internet/Intranet applications using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, SASS, React.js, Redux.js MeetingW3C standards. Excellent analytical and logical programming skills with a good understanding at the conceptual level.

Professional Experience

Assistant Frontend Developer Instructor, Bootcamp

04/2023 - present | New York, United States

- Provided personalized guidance to aspiring frontend developers through one-on-one sessions, aiding them in preparing effective resumes and LinkedIn profiles to enhance their professional branding.
- Conducted individualized mock interviews, offering constructive feedback and tailored strategies to help students develop strong interview skills and boost their confidence.
- Collaborated with students in designing and executing frontend projects as part of the bootcamp curriculum, offering hands-on assistance and mentorship to ensure project success.
- Mentored students in refining their frontend coding skills, offering guidance on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and popular frontend libraries/frameworks to foster their technical proficiency.
- Delivered comprehensive lessons on interview preparation techniques, including behavioral and technical aspects, resulting in increased student performance in real job interviews.
- Assisted students in preparing for market entry by offering insights into industry trends, resume optimization, and job market navigation, leading to improved placement rates.

Front-End Developer, Gaming Pro Market

03/2023 - 06/2023 | United States, Internship

- Worked as part of the team on projects; receive regular guidance.
- Worked closely with team members to create consistent, reusable, and maintainable code; designed new software systems or updates to existing systems.
- Coordinated and participated in implementation, testing, and support.
- Responsible for understanding how their work fits into the project objectives.
- Ensured each build functions correctly on mobile, tablet, and desktop devices.

Front-End Developer, Let's Rental Car

10/2022 - 03/2023 | United States, Internship

- Followed agile & scrum methods for the development of the product.
- Involving in building multiple UI components from design stage to production stage.
- Performed validation of completed sites including the debugging and testing of code.
- Designed a responsive website using Bootstrap grid system to layout contents that fit different devices including mobile, tablet and desktop.
- Cross-browser tested sites in Microsoft Edge, Safari, Firefox, Chrome and mobile browsers.

Projects

Single Page Application Project 🗷

https://github.com/beratucardy/spa-project You can visit my github for more projects and apps like this.